Guide to the Trinity College Historical Society Collection, [1492?] - 1981 UA.31.12.0002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Trinity College Historical Society collection
[1492?] - 1981
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Trinity College Historical Society
UA.31.12.0002
20 Linear Feet
In 1892, Dr. Stephen B. Weeks, a professor of history at Trinity College, organized the Trinity College Historical Society. The goals of the Society were to collect, arrange, and preserve written materials and artifacts illustrative of the history of North Carolina and the South, and to promote the study of Southern history through lectures and publications. The Society benefited from the strong leadership of two history professors, John Spencer Bassett and William Kenneth Boyd. They made wide appeals for donations of historical materials and maintained a museum to house these relics. The meetings of the Society, held several times each year, provided a forum at which students and faculty could read their research papers and discuss their ideas. The best of these papers were published, from 1897 to 1956, in the Historical Papers of the Trinity College Historical Society. The collection includes historical notes about Trinity College and the Society, correspondence, meeting announcements, administrative files, publications, speeches, and artifacts. Materials range in date from [1492?] to 1981. English.
3500 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Provenance
The Trinity College Historical Society Collection was received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1971 (A71-92), 1974 (A74-10), 1984 (A84-92), and 1992 (A92-34). Many items received by the Trinity College Historical Society are documented in the Society's minutes. However, some items listed in the minutes are no longer part of the collection. Manuscripts donated to the Society may be found in the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library at Duke University.
Historical Note
In 1892, Dr. Stephen B. Weeks, a professor of history at Trinity College, organized the Trinity College Historical Society. The goals of the Society were to collect, arrange, and preserve written materials and artifacts illustrative of the history of North Carolina and the South, and to promote the study of Southern history through lectures and publications. Active membership in the Society was open to anyone connected with Trinity College or to citizens of North Carolina, while corresponding membership included any persons in any part of the world who were promoters of the study of history. In its early years, the Society benefited from the strong leadership of two history professors, John Spencer Bassett and William Kenneth Boyd. They made wide appeals for donations of historical materials and maintained a museum to house these relics. The meetings of the Society, held several times each year, provided a forum at which students and faculty could read their research papers and discuss their ideas. Speakers were also invited to give addresses on a wide variety of historical topics. The best of these papers were published, from 1897 to 1956, in the Historical Papers of the Trinity College Historical Society. The Trinity College Historical Society Collection contains material about the Society's activities until 1981. Although there is no documentation on the official end of the Society, the Richard L. Watson, Jr., Papers held by Duke University Archives contains meeting announcements and notes about the Trinity College Historical Society until 1986.
Collection Overview
The collection includes a wide variety of material concerning the Trinity College Historical Society and ranges in date from [1492?] to 1981. The material includes historical notes, about Trinity College and the Trinity College Historical Society and includes transcribed notes, rosters, lists of donations, records, reviews of activities, stationary, and clippings. The correspondence and meeting announcements, [1926]-1981, includes general correspondence about the business of the Trinity College Historical Society and announcements and publicity for upcoming meetings. The administrative files, 1892-1978, includes minutes of the meetings held by the Trinity College Historical Society, and files kept by the presidents, secretaries, and treasurers of the Society. Publications, 1897-1979, include copies of the Historical Papers of the Trinity College Historical Society and newsletters published from 1978-1979. Speeches, 1904-[1980], include notes, original manuscripts, and copies of speeches and papers presented at the meetings of the Trinity College Historical Society. The artifacts, [1492?]-1918, include items collected from all aspects of American life. These relics range from coins and medals, to wooden shoe soles, to a piece of what was thought to be Christopher Columbus's flag.
In January 2007, Box 20 and folders 170 and 173 were transferred to the North Carolina Museum of History in Raleigh, North Carolina.
Related Material
Artifacts Collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
John Spencer Bassett Collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
William Kenneth Boyd Papers.
University Archives, Duke University.
Ninety Nineteen (9019) Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Richard L. Watson, Jr., Papers.
University Archives, Duke University.
Bibliography
Tilley, Nannie May. The Trinity College Historical Society, 1892-1941. Durham, N.C.: Duke University Press, 1941
Collectors and collecting -- United States; Southern States -- Civilization; North Carolina -- History; Southern States -- History -- Sources; Weeks, Stephen Beauregard, 1865-1918; Bassett, John Spencer, 1867-1928; Boyd, William Kenneth, 1879-1938; Trinity College Historical Society; Trinity College Historical Society; Duke University -- History; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.)
- Historical Notes, 1890-1967
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes historical notes about Trinity College, 1890-1901, and the Trinity College Historical Society, 1891-1967, (notes are not complete for all years). Includes transcribed notes from the Trinity Chronicle, rosters, lists of donations, records, reviews of activities, stationary, and clippings.
  - Trinity College history, 1890-1901 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Trinity College Historical Society, 1891-1925 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Trinity College Historical Society's list of donations, 1904-1915 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Record of books put into the Trinity College library by the Trinity College Historical Society, 1909-1919 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Review of Trinity College Historical Society activities, 1932-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Membership rosters, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Clippings 1940-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Stationary samples, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence and Meeting Announcements, [1926]-1981
  Includes general correspondence about the business of the Trinity College Historical Society and announcements and publicity for upcoming meetings.
  - Correspondence, [1926] (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Meeting Announcements and minutes, 1932-1940 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence and meeting announcements, 1955-1959 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Meeting announcements, 1955-1980 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence and meeting announcements, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Meeting announcements, 1962-1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence and meeting announcements, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence and meeting announcements, 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence and meeting announcements, 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Meeting announcements, 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Meeting announcements, 1967-1977 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Meeting announcements, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Meeting announcements, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence and meeting announcements, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Meeting announcements, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Administrative Files, 1892-1978
  Includes minutes of the meetings held by the Trinity College Historical Society, and files kept by the presidents, secretaries, and treasurers of the Society. Records are not available for all years.
  - Minutes of meetings
    - 1892-1901 (Oversize-box 4, Folder 36)
    - 1911 (Oversize-box 4, Folder 37)
    - 1911-1912 (Oversize-box 4, Folder 38)
    - 1934-1940, 1947 (Oversize-box 4, Folder 39)
    - 1939-1967 (Oversize-box 5, Folder 40)
    - Minutes and reports, 1955 (Oversize-box 6, Folder 41)
    - 1967-1978 (Oversize-box 6, Folder 42)
  - Officers' Reports
    - President's Notes, 1946-1958.Includes 2 copies of Nannie May Tilley's book, The Trinity College Historical Society. Durham, N.C.: Duke University Press, 1941. (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Secretary's File, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Treasurers' Reports, 1965-[1980] (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Secretary's File, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Secretary's File, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Secretary's File, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Program questionnaires (representative samples), 1971 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Secretary's File, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Preliminary Questions, undated (Box 7, Folder 51)
- Publications, 1897-1979
  The Trinity College Historical Society sought to encourage scholarship and writing on Southern history by publishing the best student and faculty papers in its Historical Papers of the Trinity College Historical Society. These papers were published from 1897-1956, with no publications from 1901-1904. Not all issues of the Historical Papers are contained in this collection. A complete set may be found in University Archives. The Society also published a newsletter of its activities from 1978-1979.
  - Historical Papers of the Trinity College Historical Society
    - Series I. 1897 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Series IV. 1900 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Series VIII. 1908-1909 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Series X. 1914 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Series XI. 1915 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Series XIII. 1919 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Series XIV. 1922 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Series XV. 1925 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Series XVI. 1926 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Series XVII. 1927 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Series XX. 1936 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Series XXI. 1937 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Series XXII. 1938 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Series XXIII. 1940 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Series XXIX. 1951 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Series XXX. 1953 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Series XXXII. 1956 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Newsletters of the Trinity College Historical Society
    - Sept. 27, 1978-April 4, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 69)
- Speeches, 1904-[1980]
  The meetings of the Trinity College Historical Society included speeches given by experts on all aspects of Southern and American history and life. Students were also encouraged to present research papers. Included are notes, original manuscripts, and copies of these speeches and papers.
  - Bassett, John Spencer. What our Society May Do for N.C. History. Oct. 13, 1904 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Baldwin, Alice M. Material for the Recent History of Women's Activities in the South. Feb. 6, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Boyd, Julian. A Century and a Half of Historical Societies in America. April 9, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Colley, Frank. Legal History. Feb. 6, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Hamilton, W.B. The Especial Responsibility of Duke University. Feb. 6, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Carroll, E.M. History and Historians in the Present Crisis. Oct. 21, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Brewster, Lawrence F. An Historical Excursion into the Antebellum Past. May 11, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Quynn, Dorothy and William Quynn. Barbara Frietschie. Oct. 12, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Patton, James W. Republican Party in N.C., 1876-1895. Jan. 15, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Woodfin, Dr. Maude H. The Biography of the Historiography of William Byrd of Westover. Feb. 26, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Hammond, Dr. Geo. P. The Southwest Today. May 11, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Curtiss, John S. The Recent Revival of the Teaching of Marxism in the USSR. Jan. 14, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Reid, R.J. My Experience as a Collector. March 11, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Carter, Clarence E. Territorial Papers of the United States: An Interpretation. April 16, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Colton, Joel. The Popular Front in France. Dec. 1, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Curtiss, John S. The Russian Church and the Famine of 1921. Oct. 20, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Laprade, Dr. W.T. Problems in Writing the History of Political Parties. Feb. 15, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Speeches. May 15, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Crittenden, Christopher. Preserving Tar Heel Archives and Historical Manuscripts. Oct. 25, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Durden, Robert Franklin. The Prostate State Revisited: James S. Pike and South Carolina Reconstruction. Feb. 1952 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Bailey, Dr. Thomas A. The Revolution in American Foreign Policy. Feb. 20, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Still, Bayrd. The City in American History. April 18, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Hollyday, Frederick. Albrecht von Stosch: A Political Biography of the Bismarckian Period. May 9, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Watson, Richard L. Bishop Cannon. Oct. 20, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Notes on speeches given at dinner in honor Prof. William T. Laprade. April 24, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Laprade, Dr. W. T. Academic Freedom and Tenure in American Colleges and Universities. 7" Sound recording tape. Oct. 22, 1953. (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - On Anglo-American Law on the Frontier. Dec. 10, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Eichelberger, Gen. Robert L. The Military Situation in the Far East since WWII. Dec. 8, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Beers, Burton F. Robert Lansing. March 22, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Johnson, Allen S. Why George Grenville Taxed America. March 22, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Cappon, Lester, J. Channing and Hart: Partners in Bibliography. Nov. 8, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Ropp, Theodore. Politics and Military Conscription in the British Commonwealth. Oct. 5, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Farr, Dr. David. Canada: The Elements of Survival. Nov. 3, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - Mackesy, Piers. Lord George Germain and the War for America. Jan. 12, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - Saywell, Dr. John T. Canada at the Crossroads. Feb. 23, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Parker, Harold T. Graduate Education in History. Oct. 26, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Watson, Richard L. F.M. Simmons: Local Politician and U.S. Senator. Feb. 21, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - Scheiner, Irwin. The Ambivalence of Responsibility. [1979-1980?] (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - Scheiner, Irwin. Samurai and Headmen. [1979-1980?] (Box 9, Folder 108)
  - [Graduate Student?] Reports, undated (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - Holley J.B. Ideas and Weapons. Notes and newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - Ropp, [Theodore]. The History of Naval Strategy, undated (Box 9, Folder 111)
- Artifacts, [1492?]-1918
  The Trinity College Historical Society issued wide appeals for donations of artifacts from all aspects of American life. In 1897, a museum was created to house some of these artifacts. Many items received by the Trinity College Historical Society are documented in the Society's minutes. However, some items listed in the minutes are no longer part of the collection. Manuscripts donated to the Society may be found in the Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library at Duke University.
  - Wooden shoe soles, 1865 (Oversize-box 10, Folder 112)
  - Lock and key from Rose of Sharon Church, 1906 (Oversize-box 10, Folder 113)
  - Piece of cable used by Confederates to protect Plymouth, N.C., 1863 (Oversize-box 10, Folder 114)
  - Piece of coat of velvet, undated (Oversize-box 11, Folder 115)
  - Ballast, piece of old saucer, thought to belong to Amadas and Barlowe, [1584?] (Oversize-box 11, Folder 116)
  - Parts of scale used to weigh gold and silver, Cape Fear settlements, ca. 18th century (Oversize-box 11, Folder 117)
  - Glasses found near battlefield of Averasboro, North Carolina, [1865] (Oversize-box 11, Folder 118)
  - Piece of jet from Whitley, England, undated (Oversize-box 11, Folder 119)
  - Lamp burner used in eastern North Carolina, ca. 19th century (Oversize-box 11, Folder 120)
  - Small pair of shoes, undated (Oversize-box 12, Folder 121)
  - Wooden tatting shuttle, undated (Oversize-box 12, Folder 122)
  - Carved bowl of smoking pipe, undated (Oversize-box 12, Folder 123)
  - Brass compass, undated (Oversize-box 12, Folder 124)
  - Silver goblet, undated (Oversize-box 12, Folder 125)
  - Metal container, undated (Oversize-box 13, Folder 126)
  - World's Fair Souvenir, Columbian Exposition medal, 1893 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 127)
  - Unidentified coin, 1827 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 128)
  - World's Fair souvenir, Christopher Columbus, 1893 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 129)
  - Virginia coin, 1773 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 130)
  - American 5 cent coin, 1883 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 131)
  - British shilling, William IV, 1835 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 132)
  - British coin, George III, undated (Oversize-box 13, Folder 133)
  - Medal in honor of Rev. H.G. Leigh, founder of Randolph Macon College, undated (Oversize-box 13, Folder 134)
  - Austrian coin, 1897 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 135)
  - Greek coin, 5 lepta, 1869 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 136)
  - American Indian head penny, 1895 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 137)
  - Mexican coin, 1893 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 138)
  - Belgium 10 centimes coin, 1864 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 139)
  - Imitation of ancient roman coin, undated (Oversize-box 13, Folder 140)
  - French 50 centimes coin, 1887 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 141)
  - Nova Scotia token, 1843 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 142)
  - Puerto Rico 20 centimes coin, 1895 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 143)
  - Souvenir medal of H.W. Grady, [1895] (Oversize-box 13, Folder 144)
  - French 10 centimes coin, 1879 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 145)
  - Prussian coin, 1867 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 146)
  - German 2 pfennig coin, 1876 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 147)
  - Chinese coin, undated (Oversize-box 13, Folder 148)
  - 3 Korean coins, undated (Oversize-box 13, Folder 149)
  - [Brazilian] coin, 1868 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 150)
  - 3 Chinese coins, undated (Oversize-box 13, Folder 151)
  - Japanese coin, undated (Oversize-box 13, Folder 152)
  - 3 Congo coins, 1887, 1888, 1888 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 153)
  - Spanish coin, 1788 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 154)
  - Mexican 25 centavos coin, 1870 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 155)
  - Korean coins, 1894, 1896, 1897 (Oversize-box 13, Folder 156)
  - Fragment thought to be from the flag of Christopher Columbus, retrieved by Trinity College student at the Columbian Exposition of 1892, [1492?] (Oversize-box 14, Folder 157)
  - Gavel from Lookout Mountain, undated (Oversize-box 14, Folder 158)
  - 2 pieces of pine, containing bullets, taken from the Bentonville Battlefield, [1865] (Oversize-box 14, Folder 159)
  - Japanese ink brush used by Fung Hui So, class of 1926, when writing to his father in China, undated (Oversize-box 14, Folder 160)
  - Spoon mold, used to make pewter spoons for slaves, undated (Oversize-box 14, Folder 161)
  - Piece of wood, undated (Oversize-box 15, Folder 162)
  - Korean money bag, belonged to Rev. J.R. Moose, undated (Oversize-box 15, Folder 163)
  - Piece of pine with bullet from Hatcher's Run battlefield, [1864-1865] (Oversize-box 15, Folder 164)
  - Minnie balls and bullets from "The Crater," Petersburg, Va., [1864] (Oversize-box 15, Folder 165)
  - Paper knife from Green Hill, Louisburg, [N.C.], undated (Oversize-box 15, Folder 166)
  - Woodsmen of the World badge, Pee Dee Camp No. 227, Cheraw, S.C., undated (Oversize-box 15, Folder 167)
  - [Fraternity badge?], undated (Oversize-box 15, Folder 168)
  - Durham Athletic Association badge, undated (Oversize-box 15, Folder 169)
  - Badge worn at Red-Shirt Banquet in Laurinburg, [N.C.], 1899 (transferred to NC Museum of History) (Oversize-box 15, Folder 170)
  - Delegate's badge to the National Democratic Convention, 1892 (Oversize-box 15, Folder 171)
  - Confederate Monument unveiling badge, Raleigh, N.C., May 10, 1895 (Oversize-box 15, Folder 172)
  - D.L. Russell for Governor, campaign badge, [1897] (transferred to NC Museum of History) (Oversize-box 15, Folder 173)
  - Knights of Honor badge, 25th annual session, Washington, D.C., June 14, 1898 (Oversize-box 15, Folder 174)
  - Horse bit used by the U.S. Calvary, undated (Oversize-box 16, Folder 175)
  - Spectacles in metal case, undated (Oversize-box 16, Folder 176)
  - Mold for ball and bullet, undated (Oversize-box 16, Folder 177)
  - Unidentified ivory receptacle, undated (Oversize-box 16, Folder 178)
  - Stirrup, undated (Oversize-box 17, Folder 179)
  - Bullet mold, undated (Oversize-box 17, Folder 180)
  - Bullet mold, undated (Oversize-box 17, Folder 181)
  - Gun shell, undated (Oversize-box 17, Folder 182)
  - Fish tooth, undated (Oversize-box 17, Folder 183)
  - Covered buttons from the clothing of Louis XVI, undated (Oversize-box 17, Folder 184)
  - Buttons from the uniform of an officer in the home guard, worn during the Civil War, undated (Oversize-box 17, Folder 185)
  - Confederate pocketbook carried by Col. G.W. Flowers during the Civil War, undated (Oversize-box 18, Folder 186)
  - [Jug handle], undated (Oversize-box 18, Folder 187)
  - Powder from the Maine, undated (Oversize-box 18, Folder 188)
  - Seal of Roanoke Colony Memorial Association, 1894 (Oversize-box 18, Folder 189)
  - Ear trumpet, undated (Oversize-box 18, Folder 190)
  - White beaver hat worn by grandfather of Dr. J.C. Brown at the opening ceremonies of Brown's Schoolhouse in Randolph County, 1838 (Oversize-box 19)
  - A shirt worn in the "Red Shirt" campaign 1898 (transferred to NC Museum of History) (Oversize-box 20)
  - Scrimshaw, undated (Oversize-box 21, Folder 191)
  - Pewter wig sprayer, undated (Oversize-box 21, Folder 192)
  - 2 spoon molds, undated (Oversize-box 21, Folder 193)
  - Lamp wick trimmer, undated (Oversize-box 21, Folder 194)
  - Candle holder, undated (Oversize-box 21, Folder 195)
  - Minnie balls, undated (Oversize-box 22, Folder 196)
  - Carved wooden pipe bowl, undated (Oversize-box 22, Folder 197)
  - Powder horn, undated (Oversize-box 22, Folder 198)
  - Powder horn, undated (Oversize-box 22, Folder 199)
  - Metal container, undated (Oversize-box 22, Folder 200)
  - Samples of homespun dresses worn by women of Granville County, [1861-1865] (Oversize-box 22, Folder 201)
  - Letter from B.F. Stevens Brown to the Trinity College Historical Society describing cheque enclosed to replace one lost on the S.S. Titanic, May 14, 1912 (Oversize-box 22, Folder 202)
  - Election ballot for twenty-eighth election district, county of New York, Nov. 4, 1913 (Oversize-box 22, Folder 203)
  - Photostat of four documents belonging to the Trinity College Historical Society, 1851-1852 (Oversize-box 22, Folder 204)
  - Editorial about Gov. Samuel W. McCall of Massachusetts, Albemarle Enterprise, June 13, 1918 (Oversize-box 22, Folder 205)
  - Knife, 1831 (Oversize-box 22, Folder 206)
  - Pair of Brazilian shoes, undated (Oversize-box 22, Folder 207)
  - Bullet mold, undated (Oversize-box 22, Folder 208)